Guide to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Collection, 1876-2020 and undated, bulk 1950-2020 RL.10006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Files, 1902-2020; undated
  - Research Files, 1902-2012; 1965-1987
    - Frank Hodsoll/National Endowment for the Arts Chairman, 1981-1982 (Box 276)
    - Manuela Hoelterhoff, 1983 (Box 276)
    - Dustin Hoffman and Molly Haskell, 1972 (Box 276)
    - Jay Holman, 1981 (Box 276)
    - Thomas Hoving, undated (Box 276)
    - Robert Hughes, 1974 and undated (Box 276)
    - In Touch Radio, 1981 (Box 276)
    - Italy, 1968-1970 (Box 276)
    - Hugh Jacobson, 1979 (Box 277)
    - Japan (Japan Report newsletter), 1968 Oct. (Box 277)
    - Japan House Gallery, 1971-1981 (Box 277)
    - Java, 1981 (Box 277)
    - Senator Jacob Javits, 1980-1982 (Box 277)
    - Jekyll Island, Georgia, 1982-1983 (Box 277)
    - The Jerusalem Center, 1993 (Box 277)
    - Jessup family, 1981-1982 (Box 277)
    - Jewelry - Clarissa Mitchell, 1981-1982 (Box 277)
    - The Jewish Museum, 1963-1969 and 1981-1982 (Box 277)
    - Job creation article (U.S.), 1998 (Box 277)
    - Cletus Johnson, 1974-1976 (Box 277)
    - Philip Johnson, 1973-1982 (Box 277)
    - Kaiser's yacht, 1902 and undated (photocopy of articles) (Box 277)
    - Ivan Karp/Robert Rauschenberg, 1972-1978 and undated (Box 277)
    - Lila Katzen, 1980 (Box 277)
    - Ed Koch, 1977-1981 (Box 277)
    - Willem De Kooning, 1974-1978 (Box 278)
    - Michael Korda, New York Times, 1977 (Box 278)
    - Joseph Kosuth, 1971-1976 (Box 278)
    - Robert Kotlowitz WNET, undated (Box 278)
    - Lee Krasner, 1973-1977 (Box 278)
    - Peter Kreindler, 1977 (Box 278)
    - George Lang and Michael and Ariane Batterberry, 1976-1979 and undated (Box 278)
    - Pam Lasch, 1984 (Box 278)
    - Ralph Lauren, 1981-1983 and undated (Box 278)
    - Learning Standards for the Arts, 1996-2005 (Box 278)
    - The Lehrman Institute/public policy, 1978-1979 (Box 278)
    - Library of America, 2001 (Box 278)
    - John Lindsay, 1978 (Box 278)
    - Morris Louis, artist, 1974-1976 (Box 278)
    - Lower East Side Tenement Museum, 2005 (Box 279)
    - Charles Luce, artist, 1979 (Box 279)
    - William B. Macomber, President of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1978-1979 (Box 279)
    - Manet/Metropolitan Museum Press Kit, 1983 (Box 279)
    - Marlborough Gallery, undated (Box 279)
    - Esther Margolis, "How to Organize Your Happiness," 1983 (Box 279)
    - Mark Taper Forum, 1979-1980 (Box 279)
    - Marriage/divorce, 1972 (Box 279)
    - Massachusetts, 1978 (Box 279)
    - Master Drawings, 2001-2002 (Box 279)
    - Ron Master/graphics, 1974-1975 (Box 279)
    - Master's Degree in Folk Art Studies, New York University, 1981 (Box 279)
    - Materials about the White House, 1962-1964 (Box 279)
    - Robert Mayer, Executive Director of the New York State Council on the Arts, 1977-1978 (Box 279)
    - John Mazzola, Lincoln Center Head, 1967-1982 (Box 279)
    - Medicine and morality, 1968 (Box 279)
    - Richard Meier, 1972-1985 (Box 279)
    - Golda Meir article, 1973 (Box 279)
    - Jonas Mekas/Ken Jacobs, 1976-1978 (Box 280)
    - Memorial/preservation clippings, 2001-2004 (Box 280)
    - Miami, 1983 (Box 280)
    - Miami-Dade Preservation League, impressions, 1981 (Box 280)
    - Annette Michelson, Art Editor, 1976 and undated (Box 280)
    - Millennium project, 1996 (Box 280)
    - Milwaukee, 1975-1979 and undated (Box 280)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974-1982 (Box 280)
    - Missions, 1967 (Box 280)
    - Mississippi, 1979 (Box 280)
    - Missouri, Saint Louis, 1979 (Box 280)
    - Herbert Mitgang, undated (Box 280)
    - Henry Moore, 1968-1978, 1983 (Box 280)
    - Sandy Moore, black women architects, 1981 (Box 281)
    - Montana, 1982 (Box 281)
    - John Monteith and Suzanne Rand, 1979 (Box 281)
    - Morgan Library/Michelangelo, 1979 (Box 281)
    - Michael Moriarty/Potter's Field, 1980 (Box 281)
    - Bernadine Morris, undated (Box 281)
    - The Murray and Isabella Rayburn Foundation, 2003 (Box 281)
    - Museum of African Art, 1967-1977 (Box 281)
    - Museum of the American Indian, 1977-1979 and undated (Box 281)
    - Museum of Art, Rhode Island School of Design, 1974-1979 (Box 281)
    - Museum of Continental Craft, B. Rockefeller/P. Smith, 1979 (Box 281)
    - Museum flyers, 2002 and undated (Box 281)
    - Museum of Graphic Art, 1966 (Box 281)
    - Museum of Modern Art, circa 1984 (Box 282)
    - Museums, 1971 (Box 282)
    - National Museum of African American History, 2002 (Box 282)
    - National Museum of the American Indian, 2002 (Box 282)
    - National Museum Services Board, Lee Kimche and George Seybolt, 1977-1978 (Box 282)
    - The National Museum of Women in the Arts, 1982-1983 (Box 282)
    - National Theatre, London, 1977 (Box 282)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation annual report, 1984 (Box 282)
    - National Video Industries, 1988 (Box 282)
    - Natural History Museum, 1974-1979 (Box 282)
    - Lowell Nesbitt, undated (Box 282)
    - Pamela Nelson, 2002-2003 (Box 282)
    - Louise Nevelson, eightieth birthday, 1979-1980 (Box 282)
    - Louise Nevelson remembered, 1989 (Box 283)
    - Louise Nevelson, seventy-fifth birthday, 1975 (Box 283)
    - Louise Nevelson stamps, 2012 (Box 283)
    - New faces, 1968-1970 (Box 283)
    - New Mexico, 1980-1982, 2 folders (Box 283)
    - The New Museum, 1981-1983 (Box 283)
    - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1980 (Box 283)
    - New York Botanical Garden, 1979 (Box 283)
    - New York City/American Institute of Architects, 1980 (Box 283)
    - New York City, Economics and Arts Policy, 1975-1978 (Box 283)
    - New York Council for the Humanities minutes, 1979, folder 1 of 2 (Box 283)
    - New York Council for the Humanities minutes, 1979, folder 2 of 2 (Box 284)
    - New York film production, 2005 (Box 284)
    - New York Historical Society, 1980 (Box 284)
    - New York Public Library, 1973-1977 (Box 284)
    - New York State/education, 1984 (Box 284)
    - New York University, 1981 (Box 284)
    - New York University Institute of Fine Arts, 1959-1976 (Box 284)
    - Barnett Newman, 1965-1976 (Box 284)
    - Edwin Newman, 1976 (Box 284)
    - Michael Newton, 1979-1987, 2 folders (Box 284)
    - News media values, 1999 (Box 284)
    - Next - book proposal (one page), circa 1990s (Box 284)
    - Waldemar A. Nielson, undated (Box 284)
    - Isamu Noguchi, 1975 (Box 284)
    - Kenneth Noland, 1967-1978, folder 1 of 2 (Box 284)
    - Kenneth Noland, 1967-1978, folder 2 of 2 (Box 285)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art, Raleigh, N.C., 1980-1981 (Box 285)
    - Not-for-profit organizations (IRS information release), 1981? (Box 285)
    - Georgia O'Keefe, 1970-1977 (Box 285)
    - Claes Oldenburg, 1969-1976 (Box 285)
    - The Open Channel, 1972 (Box 285)
    - Dennis Oppenheim, 1976-1977 (Box 285)
    - The Orient travel, 1980-1983 (Box 285)
    - Other landmarks organizations and committees, 1987-1991 (Box 285)
    - The Pace Gallery, Arnold Glimcher, 1980 (Box 285)
    - Pace Gallery "Beginnings and Ends," 1994-1995 (Box 285)
    - Painters of the Humble Truth exhibit, Tulsa, Oklahoma, and Christie's auction of World Museum collection, Oklahoma, 1981-1982 (Box 285)
    - William S. Paley, 1968-1978 (Box 285)
    - Fred Papert/Alan Sanger, 1976-1978 (Box 285)
    - Joseph Papp, 1977-1979 (Box 285)
    - Fred Papert, 1978 (Box 285)
    - Betty Parsons, 1968-1976 (Box 286)
    - Patrons of Diplomacy: Diplomatic Reception Rooms publicity packet (funding request), United States Department of State, circa 2010, 2 copies (Box 286)
    - I. M. Pei, 1980-1984 (Box 286)
    - Beverly Pepper, 1983 (Box 286)
    - Performing arts diversified, 1988 (Box 286)
    - Edward (Ted) S. Perry, 1975-1977 (Box 286)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1982 (Box 286)
    - Political clippings, 2001-2004 (Box 286)
    - Jackson Pollack, 1967-1977 (Box 286)
    - Polshek interview, 2005 (Box 286)
    - Polshek and Partners: additions to landmarks, 1987 (Box 286)
    - Barry Popik information, 1913-1995 (Box 286)
    - Preservation Society of Newport Rhode Island, 1981 (Box 286)
    - President's Committee on the Arts and Humanities, 1982 (Box 286)
    - Programs, 1982 (Box 286)
    - P.S. 1- Institute for the Art and Urban Resources, 1976-1978 (Box 286)
    - Public Art Fund, 1980-1981 (Box 286)
    - Public interest, public relations, 1980 (Box 286)
    - The Queen's collection, 1968-1977 (Box 286)
    - Queens, New York, 1983 (Box 286)
    - Michael Quigley, 1978-1980 (Box 287)
    - Dan Rather, 1986 (Box 287)
    - Robert Rauschenberg, 1963-1977 (Box 287)
    - Joyce Ravid, 1999 (Box 287)
    - Regional planning, 1989 (Box 287)
    - Reform of the international monetary system, 1986 (Box 287)
    - Renata Scotto, 1976-1977 (Box 287)
    - Renwick Gallery, 1980-1982 (Box 287)
    - Restaurants/food, 1975-1984, 2 folders (Box 287)
    - Rhode Island, 1981-1984 (Box 287)
    - Richard Gray Gallery, David Hockney, 2002 (Box 287)
    - Ivor Richard - United Nations, Lawrence O'Keefe- British Information Services (Laurence Halley), 1976-1978 (Box 287)
    - Chita Rivera, undated (Box 287)
    - Larry Rivers, 1954-1979 (Box 287)
    - Warren Robbins, Lamp Unto My Feet, 1975-1983 (Box 287)
    - Dorothy Rockburne, 1971 and 1977 (Box 288)
    - Nelson Rockefeller, 1965-1971 (Box 288)
    - Rogan, 1983 (Box 288)
    - Roma Spirit information packet, undated (Box 608)
    - Rome, 1983 (Box 288)
    - Harold Rosenberg, 1978 (Box 288)
    - James Rosenquist, 1970-1977 (Box 288)
    - Tony Rosenthal, 1974-1977 (Box 288)
    - Arthur Ross, 1980 (Box 288)
    - Mark Rothko, 1978-1985 (Box 288)
    - Royal wedding, 1981 (Box 288)
    - Peter/Thomas Rubin, 1978-1983 (Box 288)
    - Helena Rubinstein, 1976-1977 (Box 288)
    - Lewis Rudin, 1980 (Box 289)
    - Beverly Russell, 1972 (Box 289)
    - Robert Ryman, 1968-1977 (Box 289)
    - Doctor Lee Salk, 1977-1979 (Box 289)
    - Richard Salomon, 1976-1982 (Box 289)
    - Lucas Samaras, 1971-1980 (Box 289)
    - John Samuels/ Beaumont City Center, 1978-1979 (Box 289)
    - Saint Peter's Church, 1982 (Box 289)
    - San Antonio, Texas, undated (Box 289)
    - Sant'Angelo, 1977 (Box 289)
    - The Santa Fe Festival Theatre, 1981-1982 (Box 289)
    - Savannah, Georgia, 1983 (Box 289)
    - Scandinavia, 1975-1982, 2 folders (Box 289)
    - Scandinavia today, 1982-1983 (Box 289)
    - Julian Schnabel, 1999 (Box 290)
    - Gerald Schoenfeld, 1965-1978 (Box 290)
    - Tony Schwartz, 1976 (Box 290)
    - Science Attach program, 1975 (Box 290)
    - Scotland, undated (Box 290)
    - Scotland/Stobo Castle, undated (Box 290)
    - Barnabas Sears, 1971 (Box 290)
    - George Segal, 1970-1977 (Box 290)
    - Martin E. Segal, 1977, 1981 (Box 290)
    - September Eleventh Memorial clippings, 2004 (Box 290)
    - Richard Serra, 1974-1985 (Box 290)
    - Ben Shahn, 1979 (Box 290)
    - Jackie Simone, 1975-1978 (Box 290)
    - Singular Voices II suggestions, 1997 (Box 290)
    - David Smith, 1976 (Box 290)
    - Liz Smith, undated (Box 290)
    - Paul Smith, 1976-1977 (Box 290)
    - Tony Smith, 1983 (Box 290)
    - Smithsonian's Air and Space Museum, 1979 (Box 291)
    - Smithsonian's Museum of the American Indian, 1974-1978 (Box 291)
    - Snug Harbor Cultural Center, 1980 (Box 291)
    - SoHo guide, 1995 (Box 291)
    - Stephen Sondheim, circa 1970s (Box 291)
    - South Carolina, 1982-1983 (Box 291)
    - South Dakota, 1974-1982 (Box 291)
    - South Street Seaport Museum, 1980 (Box 291)
    - Raphael Soyer, 1967-1977 (Box 291)
    - Spas, 1983 (Box 291)
    - Sports book, 1994 (Box 291)
    - Frank Stanton, 1980 (Box 291)
    - Roger Starr, 1976-1977 (Box 291)
    - Saul Steinberg, 1975-1978 (Box 291)
    - Gloria Steinem, 1995 (Box 292)
    - Ellen Stewart -- La Mama Theatre, 1979 and undated (Box 292)
    - Deborah Szekely, 1981 (Box 292)
    - Mark Taper Forum, 1979-1980 (Box 292)
    - William Tarr Ideas for Artists sketch series, 1972-1973 (Box 292)
    - Mark Tashkovich: In the Town Where I Was Born: Pound Ridge published essays, 1990 (Box 292)
    - Joshua Taylor, 1975 (Box 292)
    - Television, 1971-1972 (Box 292)
    - Television, art and ethics materials, 1971-1975 (Box 292)
    - Television proposals [programs proposed by Diamonstein-Spielvogel], 1987-1991 (Box 292)
    - Wayne Thiebaud, 1971 (Box 292)
    - Tamara B. Thomas, 1972-1979 and undated (Box 292)
    - Lionel Tiger, 1981, 1997-1999 (Box 292)
    - Susanna Torre, undated (Box 292)
    - Marietta Tree, 1981 (Box 292)
    - Trudy Show, 1977 and undated (Box 292)
    - Alice Tully, 1969 (Box 292)
    - Alice Tully and Charles Wadsworth, 1978 (Box 292)
    - Bill Tunnessen, 2003 (Box 292)
    - Joanna Underwood, 1998 (Box 292)
    - Robin Utterback print, 1992 (Box 292)
    - Dr. George E. Vaillant, 1966, 1972 and 1977 (Box 292)
    - Venturi/Denise Scott Brown, 1970-1979 (Box 292)
    - Vice President's residence [Quayle's renovations], 1990 (Box 292)
    - Edward Villella, 1971-1978 (Box 292)
    - Diane Waldman, 1978 (Box 292)
    - Walker Arts Center, 2003 (Box 292)
    - Phyllis Wagner, 1978 (Box 293)
    - John Walker: Recent Paintings exhibit catalog, 2014 (Box 608)
    - Martha Wallace, Henry Luce Foundation, 1978 (Box 293)
    - Washington D.C., 1975-2005 (Box 293)
    - Washington D.C. materials (Washington Monument, JFK Library, Homeland Security), 1968-2002 (Box 293)
    - Washington D.C. oversize materials, 1968-2002 (Box 178)
      Two pamphlets and two photographs.
    - Ed Watkins Photography, 2005 (Box 293)
    - John Weber, 1975 (Box 293)
    - Weddings/brides article (clippings, notes, drafts), 1970-1971 (Box 293)
      Research for Good Housekeeping article, 1971.
    - Harry Weese, 1974 (Box 293)
    - Western Heritage Museum, Omaha, 1979 (Box 293)
    - Jaqueline Wexler, 1969-1970 (Box 293)
    - Teddy White, 1978 (Box 293)
    - White House and President's Park design plan, 2000 (Box 293)
    - Walter Muir Whitehill, 1978 (Box 293)
    - Tom Wicker, 1978 (Box 293)
    - Wilhelm Analog and Digital Color Print Materials Reference Collection guide, 2013 (Box 608)
    - Williamsburg, 1978-1979 (Box 293)
    - Women film directors, undated (Box 293)
    - Women/men/gender, 1967-1970 (Box 293)
    - Women - clippings, notes, drafts, 1969-1972 (Box 293)
      Contains some memorabilia from protests (fliers and clippings), clippings about feminism and women's issues, early feminist articles in mainstream publications, notes, and drafts of article by Diamonstein-Spielvogel.
    - Lois Wyse, 1980-1985 (Box 294)
    - Jan Yoors, 1961-1980 and undated (Box 294)
    - Mike Yudin, 1982 (Box 294)
  - Teaching, 1953-2004; bulk 1953-1986; 8
    Contains reports, catalogs, correspondence, notes, announcements, and other general materials pertaining to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's career as an elementary school teacher in Virginia and a lecturer and guest speaker in New York, particularly at hte New School for Social Research, where she taught a series of courses on the arts. Original folder titles have been retained.
    - Columbia University -- Kitty Hart, 1979 (Box 294)
    - Day Elementary School's teaching appointment, 1955 (Box 294)
    - Emerson College annual reports and course catalogs, 1976-1981 (Box 294)
    - Hunter College correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 294)
    - Hunter College, Richard Huber, 1980 (Box 294)
    - Hunter College, Inside New York, 1976 (Box 294)
    - Hunter College, Inside the Media, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 294)
    - Hunter College list of interviews conducted, undated (Box 76)
    - Juilliard School commencement, 1967 (Box 294)
    - Miss Porter's School, 1981-1983 (Box 294)
    - New School for Social Research: American Architecture Now series, 1979-1982 (Box 294)
    - New School for Social Research: Board acceptance, 2004 (Box 294)
    - New School for Social Research: Fall class announcements, 1977 (Box 294)
    - New School for Social Research: General materials, 1977 (Box 294)
    - New School for Social Research: Ideas, circa 1980s (Box 294)
    - New School for Social Research: Inside New York's Art World course advertisements, 1978 (Box 294)
    - New School for Social Research: Inside New York's Art World, course advertisements, schedule, correspondence, general materials (Box 76)
    - New School for Social Research: Metropolitan Museum of Art Lecture Series, 1976-1984 (Box 295)
    - New School for Social Research: Spring class announcements, 1977 (Box 295)
    - New School for Social Research: Spring class announcements, 1978 (Box 295)
    - New York University -- Evening with Louise Nevelson, 1980-1981 (Box 295)
    - Newport News High School, 1953-1959 (Box 295)
    - Parsons School, general materials, 1982 (Box 295)
    - Parsons School of Design, The Van Day Truex Lectures, 1980 (Box 76)
      Includes promotional posters
    - Parsons School, 90th birthday program, 1986 (Box 295)
- Art and Architecture Project Files, 1876-2016
  This series is divided into specific projects, whose files typically contain correspondence, clippings, notes, photographs, slides, interviews, printed materials and other administrative files chiefly pertaining to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's television programs, books, and exhibits whose theme focused mainly on architecture as livable art, predominantly in New York and the United States. Some of the materials also speak to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's strong interest in adaptive reuse and historic preservation.
  Materials with earliest dates are from newspaper clippings or copies of clippings used in research. Similar materials pertaining to specific projects, organizations or other activities are included with those materials in other series in the collection; however, a small amount may be present throughout this section.
  Numerous interviews and program clips corresponding to these manuscript materials are located in the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials Collection.
  - American Architecture Now, 1963-1995; 1
    Subseries contains correspondence files, clippings, many notes, photographs and slides, interviews, drafts, transcripts, printed materials and administrative files relating to American Architecture Now, a television series and corresponding book based on Diamonstein-Spielvogel's interviews of prominent architects. There are occasionally materials embedded in the folders that refer to a project sequel, American Architecture Now II.
    The videotaped oral history interviews were conducted in spring 1980 by Diamonstein-Spielvogel at the Parsons School of Design, and included architects Edward Larrabee Barnes, Jonathan Barnett, Frank Gehry, Paul Goldberger, Michael Graves, Charles Gwathmey, Hugh Hardy, Richard Meier, Charles Moore, I.M. Pei, Cesar Pelli, James Stewart Polshek, John Portman, Robert A.M. Stern, and Richard Weinstein.
    Arranged into three subseries: General Working Files, Research Files, and Transcripts. General Working Files and Research Files are arranged alphabetically by folder title. The Transcripts Subseries is arranged alphabetically by interviewee name. Original folder titles have been retained throughout.
    Numerous interviews and show clips corresponding to these manuscript materials are located in the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials Collection.
    - General Working Files, 1974-1984; 1
      - B. Dalton book signing party, 1980 (Box 296)
      - E.L. Barnes interview in Interiors, 1980 (Box 296)
      - Bloomingdale's window display, 1980-1981 (Box 296)
      - Book corrections for galley, circa 1980 (Box 296)
      - Book introduction, 1980 (Box 296)
      - Book invitation lists for New York opening, 1979-1980 (Box 296)
        Contains lists of attendees from other cultural programs, often annotated by Diamonstein-Spielvogel.
      - Book jacket copy, circa 1980 (Box 296)
      - Brown University exhibition, 1983 (Box 296)
      - Brown University exhibition, two posters, 1983 (Box 179)
      - Completed biographical information sheets, circa 1980 (Box 296)
      - Copyright registration, 1981-1983 (Box 296)
      - Correspondence and notes, 1979-1982 (Box 296)
        Also includes information on American Architecture Now II and Handmade in America.
      - Exhibition correspondence, 1982 (Box 296)
      - Exhibition proposal, circa 1981 (Box 296)
      - Flow charts, 1980 (Box 296)
      - Fogg Museum forum, 1981 (Box 296)
      - General form file, 1968, 1979 (Box 296)
      - Paul Goldberger correspondence, 1980 (Box 296)
      - Leo Castelli show, 1980 (Box 296)
      - Form letters, unused photographs, circa 1982 (Box 296)
      - Letters of interest in tapes, 1981 (Box 296)
      - Letters of praise, 1980 (Box 296)
      - Magazines requesting interviews, 1980 (Box 296)
      - Mailing list labels, 1980 (Box 296)
      - Mailing list sources of names, circa 1980 (Box 297)
      - Marketing proposal packet, Corporation for Entertainment and Learning, 1983 (Box 297)
        Packet includes introduction to project, biographies of interviewees, letters of appreciation, reviews, and the proposal.
      - Richard Meier in Interiors, 1980 (Box 297)
      - Miscellaneous articles, 1974-1980 (Box 297)
      - Sherrie Murphy correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 297)
      - New School/Parson's dinner, 1980 (Box 297)
      - Participant correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 297)
      - I. M. Pei interview in Interiors, 1980 (Box 297)
      - Portman, Barnett, Weinstein interview questions, 1980 (Box 297)
      - Three posters, circa 1982 (Box 598)
      - Poster, circa 1982 (Oversize-folder 1)
      - Poster, event invitations, 1980 (Box 76)
      - Press kit, 1980-1982 (Box 297)
      - Press kit poster, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1980-1982 (Box 179)
      - Publicity, 1980-1982 (Box 297)
      - Questions for interviews, 1979 (Box 297)
      - Release forms, 1980 (Box 297)
      - Rizzoli materials, 1979-circa 1982 (Box 297)
      - Rizzoli materials, two posters, circa 1982 (Box 179)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1980-1981 (Box 297)
      - Scanlon and Menken, Limited, 1983-1984 (Box 297)
      - Scrapbook items, 1979-1980 (Box 297)
        Contains a sampling of American Architecture Now materials set aside for possible inclusion in a scrapbook.
      - Scrapbook items, 1980-1981 (Box 298)
      - Screen shots of interviews (black-and-white stills), 1980 (Box 298)
      - Roger Smith correspondence, 1982 (Box 298)
      - Barbara Strauch correspondence, 1980 (Box 298)
      - Urban Center book reception, 1980 (Box 298)
      - Video circulation budget, 1980-1982 (Box 298)
      - Video information, 1979-1980 (Box 298)
        Includes information for multiple interview series in the arts conducted by Diamonstein-Spielvogel, including Handmade in American and American Architecture Now, such as lists of lighting and equipment, tape content, notes on video content and production, and an order form for Handmade in America that includes information about American Architecture Now, then underway.
      - Visual request letters, undated (Box 298)
      - Who Shapes Our Spaces? transcript and correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 298)
      - Solveig Williams correspondence, 1983 (Box 298)
      - Windsor video correspondence, 1980 and 1983 (Box 298)
    - Research Files, 1963-1995; 2
      - John Barnett, 1968-1971 (Box 298)
      - General research files, 1970-1981, 1995, folder 1 of 2 (Box 298)
      - General research files, 1970-1981, 1995, folder 2 of 2 (Box 299)
      - General research files, poster, 1984 (Box 179)
      - Frank Gehry, 1976-1979 (Box 299)
      - Michael Graves, 1972-1979, 2 folders (Box 299)
      - Charles Gwathmey, 1977-1979 (Box 299)
      - Hugh Hardy, 1970-1980, folder 1 of 2 (Box 299)
      - Hugh Hardy, 1970-1980, folder 2 of 2 (Box 300)
      - Hugh Hardy, two copies of New York Times Magazine, 1970-1980 (Box 380)
      - Charles Moore, 1976-1980 (Box 300)